fastpencil.com 2011-12-31

# FastPencil Privacy Policy

###  Definition and Collection of Personally Identifiable Information 

Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”) is information that uniquely identifies a person such as your name, email address, birth date, gender, ZIP code, occupation, industry, and personal interests. When you register with FastPencil, and sign in to our website, you are not anonymous to FastPencil. 

FastPencil collects personal information when you (i) register with FastPencil, (ii) use FastPencil products or services, (iii) visit FastPencil pages, and (iv) visit the pages of certain FastPencil partners. 

FastPencil collects information about your transactions with us and with some of our service providers. 

###  Third Party Sites 

The FastPencil website contains links to third party websites, which are not under the control of FastPencil, and FastPencil is not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of any third party website. If you provide any PII on a third party website, your PII will be collected by the third party and subject to the privacy policy of that third party. 

###  Collection of Technical Information 

A cookie is a text of data file, stored on your computer. It is placed on your computer’s hard drive by your web browser when you visit a web site. You can set the preferences in your web browser to allow, or not allow, a web site to store a cookie on your computer. Most browsers allow you to set your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. If you set your browser to “reject all cookies”, you will not be able to use all the FastPencil products and services. FastPencil automatically receives and records information from your computer and browser, including your IP address, FastPencil cookie information, software and hardware attributes, and the page you request. 

###  FastPencil Use of Cookies 

FastPencil uses cookies for several purposes, including without limitation, to: (i) access your information and preferences to provide you with access to your account and customized content, (ii) conduct research to improve FastPencil's products and services, (iii) support technical requirements and security measures, (iv) conduct anonymous and aggregate reporting for internal and external purposes, and (v) detect potential misuse of the FastPencil website. 

FastPencil uses session ID cookies, which confirm users are logged in, and are deleted when the user closes the browser. If you select the “Remember Me” option when you login, FastPencil uses a persistent cookie to store your login ID (but not your password) to allow you the FastPencil website to identify you when you return. 

###  Use of PII 

FastPencil may share your PII with third parties to provide you with products and services available on or through the FastPencil website. You expressly consent to the sharing of your PII with FastPencil’s contractors and service providers (“FastPencil Service Provider”) for the sole purpose of providing and servicing and products or services ordered by you on the FastPencil website. Any PII shared with a FastPencil Service Provider will only be shared subject to limited use for the sole purpose of providing the subject products or services. 

###  Marketing Communications 

FastPencil may, from time to time, send you marketing communications from FastPencil, or trusted third parties that offer products or services we believe might be of value to you (“Marketing Messages”). You can opt out of receiving future Marketing Messages by following the unsubscribe instructions contained in any Marketing Message you receive. 

FastPencil retains the right to send you certain messages relating to the FastPencil website and products and services contained therein (“Service Announcements”), including without limitation technical and administrative messages, service announcements, and other messages that are considered important to the use of your FastPencil account. You are not able to opt-out of receiving Service Announcements. 

###  User Generated Content 

Content that you contribute for your books or other published material (“Published Material”) may contain PII, and you may choose to share that Content and PII with other FastPencil users, or the general public. 

The FastPencil website contains certain forums and locations which allow users to form online relationships, send messages, post comments and share certain information (“User Generated Content”). Such User Generated Content may contain PII, which will be visible to FastPencil users, or the general public. 

###  Security 

FastPencil has commercially reasonable security measures in place to help protect your PII, however, no technical system can be guaranteed to be completely secure. You acknowledge and agree that any PII provided to FastPencil is so provided solely at your own risk, and FastPencil has no legal or financial liability to you arising out of or from your PII. If you believe that the security of your PII has been compromised, you must immediately notify us at support@fastpencil.com. [security@fastpencil.com](mailto:%73%65%63%75%72%69%74%79@%66%61%73%74%70%65%6e%63%69%6c.%63%6f%6d). 

###  Children 

**FastPencil’s services and site are not intended for children under the age of 13 years and FastPencil does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13.**

###  Disclosure of PII 

FastPencil may disclose PII in the following situations: (i) as required under applicable law; (ii) to comply with legal process; (iii) to respond to governmental requests, including requests from law enforcement and regulatory authorities; (iv) to enforce our terms and conditions; (v) to protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of FastPencil or third parties; and (vi) to pursue legal remedies against you or third parties. 

###  Transfer of PII 

FastPencil may transfer PII in the event of a corporate change of control, including without limitation any merger, acquisition, sale of assets, and other disposition of the FastPencil business, assets or stock. In the event any transfer of PII, or change in our Privacy Policy occurs that will cause a materially different treatment of PII, than as set forth herein, FastPencil will notify you via email or a notice on the FastPencil website at least 30 days prior to any such change taking effect. 

###  Jurisdiction and Venue 

This Privacy Policy shall be construed In accordance with and governed by the laws of the State of California, U.S.A., without regard to principles of conflicts of law. Each party consents to the exclusive jurisdiction and venue of the courts of Santa Clara County, California, for the resolution of any action arising out of these Terms. EACH OF THE PARTIES HERETO HEREBY IRREVOCABLY WAIVES ALL RIGHT TO TRIAL BY JURY IN ANY PROCEEDING ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. 

Copyright © 2009 FastPencil, Inc. All rights reserved.
